HENRY HEIN

FRONT END DEVELOPER



095-2240-557



Henryhein.hein@gmail.com



Remote EU/Asia Timezone



www.github.com/henry-hein



henryhein.netlify.app

PROFILE

I'm electronics engineer from Canada with four years of experience seeking a full-time Front End

Developer position to extend my knowledge as a lifelong engineer. To help learn new technologies,

I built a portfolio of projects using various web languages, which can be seen in the website above.

SKILLS

HTML5 / CSS

Javascript

JQuery

React.is

RESTful API

Bootstrap

Git

GraphQL / Apollo

Mobile Responsive Design

Next.js

Solidity

Windows, Mac, Linux OS

Ether.js

Hardhat

Defi, Trading, NFTs, and DAOs

EDUCATION

(•)

Bachelor of Applied Science, Electronics Engineering

Simon Fraser University / Burnaby Sep 2012 - Dec 2017

WORK EXPERIENCE

(•)

Front End Developer

Remote

BlueCol / Jan 2022 - Present

Working as a contractor to design and develop B2B invoicing SaaS web app that consists of React, Next.js, Apollo, GraphQL, Typescript, KeystoneJS, and Git.

- Wireframing, designing, and programming mobile responsive UI/UX of the application while maintaining brand consistency
- Refactored code to improve readability and created reusable components for faster development in Next.js
- Wrote GraphQL queries and mutations to create API that interacts with clientside code

Front End Web Development

• Vancouver, Canada

Self-Learning / Aug 2021 - Present

Currently teaching myself how to program websites in HTML, CSS, JS, jQuery Bootstrap, and React. As well as cloud hosting platform like Heroku and version control software such as Git.

- Created React mobile responsive League of Legend Champion List web app that pulls data from their API and has search, filter, and carousel functionalities
- Designed and built mobile responsive currency converter that interacts with open source API using React, Bootstrap, CSS, Heroku cloud, and Git
- Built movie finder in React and Bootstrap that interacts with open source movie database API and managed versions on Git

WORK EXPERIENCE

Facilities Service Clerk

Vancouver, Canada

Simon Fraser University / Jan 2019 - Dec 2021

Working as part of SFU Surrey Facilities Team to ensure campuses operate smoothly.

- Employed teamwork, problem solving, and analysis skills to handle maintenance requests such as fixing leaks, broken doors, and hanging white boards
- Provided excellent customer service to internal SFU staffs and ensured all requests were handled in timely and respectful manner

Electronic Test Engineer

♥ Vancouver, Canada

Innovative Circuit Technology / Jan 2018 - Dec 2018

Worked as part of R&D Team, responsible for procurement, assembly, testing, documentations, and debugging power electronic systems, which lead to company savings of \$100,000 in six months.

- Created test plans, performed tests, and documented findings for magnetics for power converter systems, which decreased core temperature by 5°C
- Communicated supply chain, manufacturers, engineers, and technicians and components arrived early by average of 1 week
- Debugged and tested new high-power converter under supervision to execute test plans and created test jig that reduced setup time by 10 minutes each test

Hardware Test Engineer

Vancouver, Canada

TRIUMF / Sep 2016 - Dec 2017

Worked as part of Beamline Diagnostics Team, responsible for procurement, assembly, testing, SPICE simulation, documentations, and debugging beamline electronics.

- Diagnosed, and repaired electronic circuits, assembled mechanical casings, and created cable harnesses which improved assembly time by 5 minutes per unit
- Communicated with PCB manufacturers, component suppliers, and team members to ensure all specifications and components arrived early by average of 4 days

Embedded Systems Integrator

♀ Vancouver, Canada

LineSpect / Sep 2015 - Apr 2015

Work at a start-up company in prototyping hexcopter that inspects faults in power line. Was in charge of integrating, troubleshooting, and designing sensor electronics that reads EMF info from power lines

- Characterized Signal to Noise ratio of Ultrasound and Ultraviolet sensors and designed circuits that improved Signal to Noise ratio each sensor by 10%
- Designed and Integrated motors, sensors, antennas, and lithium battery that reduced weight of hexcopter by 10%, which improved flight time by 5%

INTERESTS

Travelling

Cooking

Basketball

Soccer

Hiking

Kick Boxing